Finding Aid for Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project Records, 1947-2003
Bentley Historical Library
- History
  - Clippings
    - Alice Lloyd Lab, 1953-1955 (Box 4)
    - Goldberg, H.J., 1952-1956 (Box 4)
    - Leatherman, R.L., 1955-1956 (Box 4)
    - Sawyer, R.A., 1952-1956 (Box 4)
    - Visitors, 1951-1955 (Box 4)
    - General, circa 1949-1962; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Development of Phoenix Project, 1948-1954; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Development Program, circa 1948-1951 (Box 4)
  - Early Documents, circa 1948-1951 (Box 4)
  - "Future" Files, 1962-1964; undated (Box 5)
  - Logo (print from Erich Walter to Jacqueline Haring), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Manuscripts, 1957; undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950-1959; undated (Box 5)
  - Name List (Donors), undated (Box 5)
  - Outline, 1948-1951 (Box 5)
  - Outstanding Contributors, 1955-1959 (Box 5)
  - Photographs (Box 5)
    (includes photographs of architectural rendering of laboratory, portraits, and Ford Reactor details)
  - Planning, Early, 1949-1951 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Project Transition Program, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Publicity, circa 1959-1962 (Box 5)
  - Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, Early (includes letters from well-known figures), 1947-1948 (Box 5)
  - To Evaluate the Future, Ron Fleming, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Twentieth Anniversary, Ford Reactor, 1977 (Box 5)
- Minutes of Meetings, 1948-2001
  The Minutes of Meetings series, 1948-2001 (3 linear ft.), includes records from the earliest planning periods through the late 1980s. It is important to note that more than a year of organization and preparation preceded the launching of the original fund-raising campaign, a campaign President Ruthven called the most important project ever undertaken by the university. This planning period is well documented in meeting and committee files. In earlier years, an executive committee advised and participated in both fund-raising and research development. By 1956, these functions were divided when a continuation committee was charged with studying how to continue the project via a second fund-raising campaign. Among its recommendations was the appointment of a strong administrative board of governors and a second body to oversee the research side of the project. Records generated by the resulting Board of Governors are the best resource for gathering information on the second campaign, while Faculty Executive Committee files illuminate the development of research and academic programs during the period. (The Board of Governors was discharged in 1962, and the Faculty Executive Committee took on a more comprehensive advisory role.) The Executive Committee files include minutes from meetings, rosters of Committee members, evaluations and determinations of grant proposals, information on the status of the Ford Reactor, financial reports related to grant funding, as well as the overall operation of the Phoenix Project.
  - Board of Governors, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Campaign Executive Committee, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Continuation Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
  - Early Meetings, 1948-1951 (Box 6)
  - Executive Committee
    - 1948-1949 (Box 6)
    - 1951-1959 (Box 6)
      (indexed)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 6)
      (with accompanying material)
  - Faculty Executive Committee (Box 7)
    - 1959-1982, 2 folders (Box 7)
      (Kerr files?)
    - 1962-1984, 1 folder (Box 7)
    - 1984-1989 (Box 7)
    - 1990-2001, 13 folders (Box 54)
  - Preliminary Planning Committee, 1948-1956; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Reactor Advisory Committee, 1958-1961 (scattered); 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Staff
    - General (sparse), 1959-1961 (Box 7)
    - Operational (sparse), 1961-1962 (Box 7)
- Development Topical Files, 1948-1962
  The Development Topical Files series, 1948-1962 (3.5 linear ft.), although varied in content, is primarily comprised of material relating to fund-raising and development. Well documented are the various strategies developed to reach potential donors, corporate and individual. Significant files include Atom Day, The Case, Chairman's Source Book, and Presentations. Presentations are, for the most part, scripted speeches directed toward specific industries or companies. The meticulously structured nature of the campaign is evident in these files, along with files documenting the work of various committees. Correspondence, including early communications to and from Ralph Sawyer, the first director of the project, lecture notes, and conference proceedings are also contained in the series. Atom Reports for example, is the title of a conference held at the university in 1953 and 1954 focusing on the social impact of nuclear energy.
  - Annual Report, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Atom Day, 1950
    - General (Box 8)
    - Planning (Box 8)
    - Speeches (Box 8)
    - Telephone Broadcast (Box 8)
  - Atom Reports (Conference), 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1948-1953 (Box 8)
  - Baird, James, 1952; undated (Box 8)
  - Beake, Harold C., undated (Box 8)
  - Bean, F.A. Foundation, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Benedum, Michael, undated (Box 8)
  - Biographies, 1950-1952 (Box 8)
  - Blockson Chemical Co., undated (Box 8)
  - Botany and Agriculture, undated (Box 8)
  - Briggs, Robert, UM Vice President, 1950 (Box 8)
    (includes group portrait taken in Charlotte, N. Carolina)
  - Brown, Harry, 1949-1950; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Campaign General and Misc., 1949-1951 (Box 8)
  - Campaign Schedules and Timing, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
  - "Case," (planning documents), 1948-1950; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Chairman's Source Book, 1948-1949; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Chamberlain, Katherine, 1949-1951 (Box 8)
  - Chase, Lee, 1950-1951 (Box 8)
  - Christmas Mailing, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Chrysler Corporation, 1950-1951 (Box 8)
  - Church of Jesus Christ, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Cleveland Shipping News, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Committees
    - Alumni Advisory Committee, 1950-1952 (Box 8)
    - Committee Members Correspondence, 1950 (Box 8)
    - Committee of 100, (campaign after 1951) (Box 8)
    - Committees of Sponsors, 1950 (Box 8)
    - Parents, 1950 (Box 8)
    - Steering, 1950-1952 (Box 8)
  - Conference Notes, 1949 (Box 8)
  - Cooley Foundation, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Cook, Grant, undated (Box 9)
  - Corporate Gift Planning, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence
    - 1947-1951 (Box 9)
    - Director, early on (Ralph A. Sawyer), 1949-1951 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Requests, Peculiar, 1951-1954 (Box 9)
  - Coulter, Glenn, 1950-1952 (Box 9)
  - Courtney, F.D., 1949 (Box 9)
  - Craig, Homer, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Crawford, William, 1949-1952 (Box 9)
  - Creed of the Michigan Memorial, undated (Box 9)
  - Cress, Earl, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Crisler, H. O., 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Cultivation Letters (Homer Ferguson), 1950 (Box 9)
  - Cyclotron, undated (Box 9)
  - Daume, Selden, 1949-1952 (Box 9)
  - Davidson, William, Foreign Chairman, 1949-1952 (Box 9)
  - Davis, R. M., undated (Box 9)
  - Dearborn Motors, 1951 (Box 9)
  - DeKeip, James, 1950 (Box 9)
  - Del Valle, Manual, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Detroit Edison, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Development Council, 1953-1957 (Box 9)
  - Diekema, Willis, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Dodge, Joseph, 1950-1958 (Box 9)
  - Dow Chemical, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Dow, David, 1949-1950 (Box 9)
  - Dryer, Rex, 1950-1953 (Box 9)
  - Dunbar, Duke, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Drafting Committee Report (development work), 1951 (Box 9)
  - Dupont, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Eisenhower, Edgar, 1950-1959 (Box 9)
  - Everett Piano Co., 1951 (Box 9)
  - Faculty Special Gifts Visits (Box 9)
  - Field Men, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Fanfolds (form letters), undated (Box 9)
  - Ferguson, Homer, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Financial
    - Distribution by amount and schools, 1951 (Box 9)
    - General, 1948-1957; undated (Box 9)
  - Follin, James, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
  - Ford Presentation, 1949-1951; undated (Box 9)
  - Form Letters, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - General Electric, undated (Box 9)
  - General Mills, Inc., undated (Box 9)
  - General Motors, 1950 (Box 9)
  - Gerber Products Co., undated (Box 9)
  - Gessner, Charles, 1950 (Box 9)
  - Gifts
    - Schedules (includes procedures), undated (Box 9)
    - Special (solicitation), undated (Box 9)
    - Summary Report, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Gilbreth, Frank, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Gomberg, Henry, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Gore, Mrs. Charles W., 1949-1952 (Box 10)
  - Goreman, Michael, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Gorman, Rocco, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
  - Greenaway, Donald, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Gries, Walter, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Graydon, Joseph, undated (Box 10)
  - Haber, William (faculty chairman), 1949-1951 (Box 10)
  - Hall, Robert Memorial, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Hall, Willard, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
  - Hallas, Howard, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
  - Ham, A. W., 1950 (Box 10)
  - Hanley, Edna, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Harris, G.C., 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Hatcher, Harlan, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Heath, Milton, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
  - Henderson, Charles, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
  - Herbert / Schoolcraft Co., 1950 (Box 10)
  - Herlihy, John, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Herrick, Vaughn, 1949-1952 (Box 10)
  - Hess, Robert, 1948-1952; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Heustis, L.C., 1951 (Box 10)
  - Hill, Carleton, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Hillery, Vernon, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Hinkley, Arthur, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Hoffman, R.J., 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Holbrook, George, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
  - Holt, William, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Honor Roll
    - First Edition, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Second Edition (includes Sawyer progress report), 1951 (Box 10)
  - Hook, Ira, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Hook, Keith, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Hoover, Earl, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
  - Horwitz, Rollo, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
  - Hudson Co., undated (Box 10)
  - Institute for Regional Research, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Inter-office Memorandums, 1950 (Box 10)
  - International Harvester Company, undated (Box 10)
  - John, W.A.P. (heart disease research), undated (Box 10)
  - Laskin Foundation, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Maybee, John, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Mayo, Rochester, Minn., 1950 (Box 10)
  - Medical Faculty, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Metal Processes, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Metal Surfaces and Coatings, Project for Improvement of, undated (Box 10)
  - Michigan Bell, undated (Box 10)
  - Minneapolis Honeywell Regulator Co., undated (Box 10)
  - Minneapolis Moline Power, undated (Box 10)
  - Minnesota Mining & Manufacturing, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Montague, Gilbert, undated (Box 10)
  - Motor Products Corp., undated (Box 10)
  - Nash, Kelvinator, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Newago Engineering, undated (Box 10)
  - Newman, Henry L. (heart disease), 1951 (Box 10)
  - Packard Motor Co., undated (Box 10)
  - Parker, James W., 1950-1957 (Box 10)
  - Parker Wolverine Co., undated (Box 10)
  - Pennington, Harry, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Phoenix the Bird, undated (Box 10)
  - Pillsbury Mills Inc., undated (Box 10)
  - Presentations
    - Corporate, Regional, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
    - Special, 1949-1951; undated; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Prine, Arthur C., (external relations), 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Proctor & Gamble, undated (Box 10)
  - Publications, 1958-1960 (Box 10)
  - Quaker Oats, undated (Box 10)
  - Reports and Lectures, Autoradiography (Gomberg?) (Box 11)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Course, June, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies, 1951 (Box 11)
    - Gomberg Lecture Notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Reports and Notes on Paper, circa 1954 (Box 11)
    - Various Lectures, undated (Box 11)
    - Watertown Arsenal Report (includes photographs), Undated (Box 11)
  - Ravenscroft Memorial, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Releases, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Rider, Bitt, undated (Box 11)
  - River Raisin Company, undated (Box 11)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, TV Show, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Sanders, Fred, undated (Box 11)
  - Six Lumber Mills in Northwest, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Smith, Fred, 1947 (Box 11)
  - Socony-Vacuum, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Speakers for Ann Arbor, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Stone, Ralph, 1949-1953 (Box 11)
  - Sullivan, Eugene, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Timkin Roller Bearing, undated (Box 11)
  - Trane Company, undated (Box 11)
  - Volker Foundation (Education), 1950-1951 (Box 11)
  - Ward, Charles, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Welber Foundation, undated (Box 11)
  - Wyandotte Chemical Corp., undated (Box 11)
- Director's Topical Files, 1950-1969
  The Director's Topical Files series, 1950-1969 (7 linear ft.), also contains a large number of development related records. More often interspersed among fund-raising related files, however, are administrative materials, proposals, and project records. Material generated from the work of various committees and subcommittees is scattered throughout the series. Significant records include papers documenting interactions with the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (AEC), such as the original proposal for a nuclear reactor, access permits, contracts, licensing, general correspondence, and communications regarding the Ford Nuclear Reactor. There are also a large number of reports, both technical and administrative, and speech files. Speech files offer concise overviews of project goals as articulated to various audiences, and at the same time, illuminate the extent to which Phoenix leadership participated in outreach and advocacy aspects of the project as it evolved. The Oppenheimer file documents Robert Oppenheimer's somewhat controversial appearance in Ann Arbor to deliver the Fagerburg address in 1962. The folder holds correspondence, transcripts, and press releases.
  - "A" Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 11)
  - Abbott Laboratories, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Accidents, 1958-1961; 2 folders (Box 11)
    (see also Channon, Fred, Accident)
  - Albrecht, Robert, 1961 (Box 11)
  - American Institute of Chemical Engineers, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Armstrong, Hugh, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Atomic Energy Commission
    - General, 1952-1960; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Access Permits, 1955-1960 (Box 11)
    - Chicago, 1958-1959 (Box 12)
    - Contract, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    - Ford Nuclear Reactor, 1952-1959 (Box 12)
    - License, 1956-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Oakridge, Tenn., 1959 (Box 12)
    - Radioisotope Development Lab, 1958 (Box 12)
    - Washington, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Atomic Industrial Forum, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - "B" Miscellaneous, 1958-1960 (Box 12)
  - Bendix Corporation, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Bixby, Glenn, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Bochnowski, Alex, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Brownell, L.E., 1957-1959 (Box 12)
  - Budget Background, 1957-1960 (Box 12)
  - Budget Material, 1957-1960 (Box 12)
  - "C" Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Campaign Drive, 1959; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Campaign Plan, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Cancer, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Catherine St. Lab, 1961 (Box 12)
  - Channon, Fred, Accident, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
    (see also Accidents)
  - Chayne, Charles, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Chrysler, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
  - Chrysler, Ford and GM Visits, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Classified Document Receipts, 1957-1961 (Box 12)
  - Cleveland Atomic Exposition, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Comins, Franklin C., 1959-1961 (Box 12)
  - Committees
    - General, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
    - Kresge Radioisotope, undated (Box 12)
    - Lists of, 1954-1955; undated (Box 12)
    - Proceedings of the Meeting of the Subcommittee on Research Reactor, March 28 and 29, 1959 (Box 12)
    - Subcommittee on Unclassified Nuclear Reactors, 1954-1957 (Box 12)
  - Conferences
    - Isotopes and Effects in Russia, 1957 (Box 12)
    - Science and Technology, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Connelly, John M., 1960 (Box 12)
  - Connely, Emmett, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Construction Fund
    - 1951 (Box 12)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 12)
  - Consumers Summer Institute, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Continuation Campaign Plan, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Cook Electric Company, 1958-1959 (Box 12)
  - Cooper, Gage R., 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Copyright, 1961-1965 (Box 12)
  - Corporations, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence (Box 13)
    (see also General)
    - 1954-1972, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Fagerburg Memorial Lecture, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous Requests, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
  - Coulter, Glenn, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Crandall, Lou, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Crawford, William B., 1959-1961 (Box 13)
  - Creal, Cecil O., 1960 (Box 13)
  - Cress, Earl, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Cress, Elmer, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Cudlip, Merlin A., 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Cunningham, Mrs. Marcus, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Cummiskey, E. A., 1955 (Box 13)
  - "D" Miscellaneous, 1956-1959 (Box 13)
  - Davidson, Halsey, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Detroit Corporations, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Detroit Kick-Off, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Development, 1960-1966 (Box 13)
  - Dickinson, Thomas, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Doan, Le, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Doty, Andrew M., 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Doyle and Hewson Proposal, undated (Box 13)
  - Dow Chemical, 1957-1958 (Box 13)
  - Eden, Paul L., 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Education, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Emergency List, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Emmons, A. H., 1959-1961 (Box 13)
  - Equipment, General, 1958-1959 (Box 13)
  - Euler, Ralph, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Exhibits, General, 1955-1959 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous, 1958-1960 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships
    - General, 1951-1959 (Box 13)
    - Corning Glass, 1954-1960 (Box 13)
    - Detroit Edison, 1954-1955 (Box 13)
    - Predoctorals, 1948-1958; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Summer Faculty Research, 1950-1951 (Box 13)
  - Field Foundation, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Films, 1959; undated (Box 13)
  - Fission Products Laboratory, 1953-1959 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
  - Ford Nuclear Reactor
    - Cost Reports, 1955-1958 (Box 13)
    - General 1953-1959 (includes, 1955 specifications) (Box 13)
  - Foreign Lectures and Visitors, 1954-1960 (Box 13)
  - Fraventhal, A. H., 1961 (Box 13)
  - French, Dean David, 1959-1961 (Box 13)
  - Fund For Peaceful Atomic Development, 1958 (Box 13)
  - Fund-raising Literature, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Furstenberg, Albert C., 1960 (Box 13)
  - "G" Miscellaneous, 1955-1961 (Box 13)
  - Gannett, J.K., 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Garsou, Julien, 1957-1960 (Box 13)
  - Gault, Harry, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
  - General, 1948-1960; 3 folders (Box 14)
    (mainly Sawyer, Gomberg, and Letterman correspondence)
  - General Electric, 1956-1959 (Box 14)
  - General Motors, 1958-1960 (Box 14)
  - Geneva, 1955 (Box 14)
  - George, Edwin, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Gifts
    - Bendix, 1955 (Box 14)
    - Chrysler Corp., 1951-1957 (Box 14)
    - Corporate Gift List, 1960 (Box 14)
    - DeWaters, Sara, 1951-1960 (Box 14)
    - Ford Motor Co., 1952-1960 (Box 14)
    - General Electric, 1953-1956 (Box 14)
    - General Motors, 1950-1955 (Box 14)
    - Libby Owens Ford Glass, 1951-1954 (Box 14)
    - Lloyd Memorial, 1952-1960 (Box 14)
    - Mason Memorial, 1954-1955 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1951-1964; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Monsanto, 1953-1955 (Box 14)
    - Packard Motor Car Co., 1953-1956 (Box 14)
    - Parke-Davis, 1953-1960 (Box 14)
    - Reports, 1959-1961 (Box 14)
    - Reynolds Metal, 1953-1960 (Box 14)
    - U.S. Rubber, 1951-1952 (Box 14)
    - Upjohn, 1952-1957 (Box 14)
    - Welch Manufacturing, 1953-1958 (Box 14)
  - Glaser, John, Nobel Prize (regarding Fagerburg lecture), 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - Gold, Louis, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Gomberg, Henry, 1953-1960 (Box 14)
  - Gotlieb, Albert, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Gottlieb, Norman, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - Graduate Students, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - Grants, 1958-1964 (Box 14)
  - Gregory, George, 1959-1960 (Box 14)
  - Grier, William, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Griffen, Glenn, 1959-1960 (Box 14)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Hall, Richard (experimental work on reactor),1961 (Box 14)
  - Hatcher, Harlan, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Hazards Evolution, undated (Box 14)
  - "I" Miscellaneous, 1957-1961 (Box 14)
  - Industrial Health, 1950-1952 (Box 14)
  - Industry Program, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
  - Insurance, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Inquiries, 1948-1959 (Box 14)
  - International Atomic Energy Agency Proposal (IAEA), 1960 (Box 14)
  - "K" Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 15)
  - Korst, Donald, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Kresge Foundation, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Kyoto University, 1956-1958 (Box 15)
  - "L" Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 15)
  - Leader, Luther, 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Leadership Suggestions (Campaign), 1949; undated (Box 15)
  - Leatherman, Roger, 1958-1960 (Box 15)
  - Lecturers (outside), 1949-1955 (Box 15)
  - Leonard Refineries, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Library List, 1960-1961 (Box 15)
  - Lists (contributors), 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Lockhead Corp., 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Luckow, William, 1957-1960 (Box 15)
  - "M" Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 15)
  - MacCarthy, Alan, 1959-1961 (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), 1959-1961 (Box 15)
  - Meeting on Research Reactors, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Meinke, Wayne, 1957-1964 (Box 15)
  - Midwest Universities Research Association, 1954-1955 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1955-1960 (Box 15)
  - Mott Foundation, 1960 (Box 15)
  - "N" Miscellaneous, 1958-1959 (Box 15)
  - National Advisory Committee, 1950-1958 (Box 15)
  - National Research Council, 1954 (Box 15)
  - National Science Foundation, 1959-1961 (Box 15)
  - National Science Foundation Life Science Wing, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Nuclear Energy Laboratory, 1961; undated (Box 15)
  - Nuclear Engineering, 1957-1959 (Box 15)
  - Nuclear Engineering Curriculum Committee, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Nuclear Fear, undated (Box 15)
  - Nuclear Power Plant, 1955-1956 (Box 15)
  - Nucleonics, Hot Lab Meeting, 1955-1960 (Box 15)
  - Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Organization, Staff, 1961; undated (Box 15)
  - Overtime, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Owens Corning, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Parke-Davis, 1958-1960 (Box 15)
  - Parker, George E., 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Perring, Raymond, 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Personnel, 1953-1956 (Box 15)
  - Pledges, 1963-1967 (Box 15)
  - Plutonium, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Potential Use of PML, 1957-1960 (Box 15)
  - Power Reactor Development Co., 1956-1958 (Box 15)
  - Preliminary Planning, 1949 (Box 15)
  - Presentations
    - 1957-1960, undated (Box 15)
    - Public Utilities, 1960 (Box 15)
    - Sloan, 1960 (Box 15)
    - X Radiation Facility, undated (Box 15)
  - Projects
    - Lists, 1958-1963; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Nonrestricted, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Physical Science, 1961 (Box 15)
    - Trichinosis, 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Proposals (Box 16)
    - Early Projects, 1947-1951; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - General, 1960-1963 (Box 16)
    - Graduate Area Program in Radiation Biology, circa 1960 (Box 16)
    - Operating Funds Proposal, 1963; 1964; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Thesis Proposals, 1953-1954; undated (Box 16)
  - Prospective Personnel, 1949-1957 (Box 16)
  - Prospects
    - General, 1949-1961 (Box 16)
    - Top, 1959-1960 (Box 16)
  - Publications, 1956-1961 (Box 16)
  - Public Relations and Promotion, 1958; undated (Box 16)
  - Publicity
    - 1950-1955, 2 folders (Box 16)
      (includes photographs of Dwight D. Eisenhower, Warren G. Austin, Gordon E. Dean)
    - Radio, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Radiation Biology Program, 1960-1962 (Box 16)
  - Radiation Policy Committee (Box 16)
  - Radioisotope Committee, 1954 (Box 16)
  - Radiological Courses, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Radiological Safety Dept., 1952-1954 (Box 16)
  - Reactor Meeting (Conference), 1969 (Box 16)
  - Reports
    - General, 1958-1969 (Box 16)
    - Aims and Purposes of the Atomic Research Program at UM, undated (Box 16)
    - Annual, 1956-1960 (Box 16)
    - Annual Mailing Lists, 1953-1955 (Box 16)
    - Board of Governors, 1961-1963; undated (Box 16)
    - Budget Report, Kerr, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
    - Budget Report, Crippen, 1960-1962 (Box 16)
    - Crippen to Zeder (Box 16)
    - Environmental Survey, Whipple, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Five and Six Year Plans, 1964-1965 (Box 16)
    - Fund for Peaceful Atomic Development, 1955-1957 (Box 16)
    - Generalized Atomic Energy Program, Whipple and Kerr, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Ground Water Survey by T. Kamash, 1959 (Box 17)